- This is the largest
amount of spider silk
that's ever been put together
for a test like this.
So I'm gonna put it to the ultimate test,
and try to be the first
person ever to swing
from spider silk.
I don't know if it's going to
hold my weight, so let's see.
In three, two, one.
(Derek yelling)
- In "Spider-Man Two,"
Peter Parker is on a runaway
train full of passengers.
And to stop it from derailing,
he stands in front of the train,
fires webs at the buildings
around him, and holds on.
The webs stretch, some of them snap,
but they do just enough
to slow down the train
and save everyone on board.
It sounds like something
straight out of a comic book.
But real spider silk,
the fiber that makes up a spider's web,
well, it truly might be this incredible.
It's reportedly stronger than
steel. It's pretty strong.
That's crazy!
And 10 times tougher than Kevlar.
To find out if that's really true,
I went to the Blackledge Spider Lab
at the University of Akron,
one of the world's
leading research centers
studying spider silk.
Before I went to the lab,
I'd always assume that
a spiderweb was made
from just one kind of silk.
But that's actually not the case.
One type of silk anchors
the web to a surface.
Another forms this stretchy spiral,
and a different sticky silk catches prey.
Once something's trapped,
the spider switches to yet
another silk to wrap it up.
- The threads are all
thinner than your hair,
so they're going to look
pretty similar to each other
unless you use a microscope.
- [Henry] All in all,
there are seven different types of silk,
but the strongest is the dragline silk,
which holds the web in its place.
- We've got the two main
structural threads in this web.
So the spokes on the wagon wheel
and the outer framework here,
that's all the dragline silk.
It's called major ampullate
silk if you want the fancy word.
- The major ampullate is that one
that commonly compared to steel?
- Yes!
- Okay.
- Absolutely.
And that's partly because it's
function in a web like this.
A bug hits it, to stop that moving bug,
most of the work is done
by the dragline silk.
- [Henry] To do this,
the dragline silk has
to be incredibly strong.
So to find out how it compares to steel,
we wanted to run a test,
but it turns out that getting
the sample isn't so easy.
All right, we've taken
a garden variety spider
and knocked it unconscious using CO2.
We brought it over here and
we put it down with tape.
I then started pulling out
the dragline silk by hand.
It's so light that you can barely feel it.
We've attached it to this
big rotating mechanism
which they custom made to milk spiders.
(bright music)
No spiders were harmed in
the making of this video.
Now that we've got our silk,
we can put one strand into a machine
that slowly pulls on our sample.
And as it pulls, we'll
monitor two key properties.
When you pull on the silk,
that force is spread over a
tiny cross-sectional area.
If you divide the force by
that area, you get the stress.
Now, as you pull, the
silk is also stretching.
To see just how much, we
divide the change in length
by the original length to get
a measure called the strain.
At first, as the stress increases,
the strain increases
roughly in proportion.
And if we stop pulling here,
the silk would spring back
to its original length.
But keep pulling and
eventually it passes a point
where some of that
stretching becomes permanent.
And it's pulling.
- [Videographer] All right.
You film that, I'm going
to be filming this.
- [Henry] And it broke.
- [Videographer] Wow!
- [Henry] Eventually, if you
keep pulling on the silk,
it will break.
And at that point, the force applied,
divided by the cross-sectional area
is called its ultimate tensile strength.
- We're at about 600 megapascals.
- [Henry] To put that in perspective,
if you had a rope of spider silk
that had a cross-sectional
area of one square centimeter,
roughly the size of your little finger,
it could support about
60,000 newtons of force.
That's the weight of a fully
grown African elephant.
And that's not even the
strongest spider silk out there.
- Breaking stress wasn't
incredible for this piece of silk.
- [Henry] Deep in the
jungles of Madagascar
lives the Darwin's bark spider.
Its diet consists of flying insects
that zip over wide rivers.
So to catch its prey,
the Darwin's bark spider
has to spin giant webs that
stretch up to 25 meters
over open water.
And to survive that kind
of distance and tension,
its silk has to be incredibly strong.
It has an ultimate tensile strength
of around 1,600 megapascals.
That's more than twice the
strength of our sample.
But experimental ultra
high strength steels
can reach an ultimate tensile strength
of nearly 3,000 megapascals.
That's about three times that
of typical dragline silk,
but steel is also about six times denser.
So for two ropes with
the same mass and length,
the silk rope has six times
the cross-sectional area.
Six times the area at
one third the strength,
well, that gives a rope that
can take twice the force
before it snaps.
This measure of strength relative to mass
is called specific strength.
And it means that for
the same mass and length,
spiderwebs can withstand
roughly twice the force
of ultra high strength
steel before breaking.
- So that's where ounce for ounce,
spider silk is quite strong.
You got to think about
what is the application
you're talking about
using this material in.
Is it somewhere where you
don't care about weight,
and you need the strength?
Then steel's going to be perfectly fine.
But if weight matters,
spider silk is really the champion there
for tensile strength.
- [Henry] But strength alone isn't enough.
To see why, look at rock climbers.
If a rock climber was just
hanging, all we would care about
was if the rope could
support their weight.
That's strength. But climbers
don't just hang, they fall.
And now the rope has to
bring them to a stop,
which means absorbing that kinetic energy.
Stop the fall in a short distance,
and the energy has to be absorbed quickly.
The forces are enormous.
Stretch it out and that same
energy is absorbed gradually,
so the forces are lower.
So to absorb more energy without snapping,
it has to stretch further.
And that's actually not so
different from spider silk.
- So a bug hits this web,
you've got to stop the flight
of that bug pretty quickly.
And you could do it by just building
a really stiff structure.
Think like a brick wall, you
throw a tennis ball against it.
You're gonna stop that ball instantly.
But that doesn't work very well
if you want to catch a meal.
- It'll bounce off.
- Because it'll just fall out.
And so it helps to slowly
decelerate the insect
so that the web has time to stick to it,
and keep the meal for
the spider to subdue.
- [Henry] So the spider silk
has to be quite stretchy.
- This piece of silk
stretched to 70% of its length
before it broke,
which is really exceptional
for dragline silk.
- [Henry] Now, every
tiny bit of stretching
absorbs a little bit of energy.
If you add all these
tiny amounts together,
the result is the total
energy the material absorbs
before breaking.
On a stress/strain graph,
it's proportional to the
area under the curve.
This is the material's toughness.
Kevlar, the material used
in bulletproof vests,
whose whole job is to take
the energy of a bullet
and spread it out before
it reaches the body, well,
it has a toughness of up to
50 megajoules per cubic meter.
Experimental ultra-high strength steel
has a toughness of around 170
megajoules per cubic meter.
But spider silk?
- This piece of silk had a toughness
of about 205 megajoules per cubic meter.
- Oh, okay. So that might
be like four times Kevlar.
But the silk from the Darwin's bark spider
can have a peak toughness of
520 megajoules per cubic meter.
That's roughly three times
the strongest steel out there,
and 10 times as tough as Kevlar.
See, Kevlar has a very
high tensile strength,
but it's also quite stiff.
Compared with stretchy spider silk,
that means that the
stress/strain graph rises sharply
and fails before it can stretch very far.
So it's not able to absorb as much energy.
And that's why spider
silk wins on toughness.
- But it's the ultimate
in green chemistry.
They're not using the high temperature,
or the caustic solvents that
most of the polymer industry
uses to make high performance threads.
They're doing it at room
temperature, inside a living body,
with the same basic building blocks
that you use to build
your hair and your skin.
- Now, the secret to spider silk's
unbelievable natural strength
lies in how those building
blocks are arranged.
If you look inside a silk fiber,
you'll find spider silk
proteins called spidroins.
In some regions,
the spidroins are arranged
in similar size and shape,
and they're closely
aligned along its length.
They're kind of like stacked egg trays.
These are nanocrystals.
In other areas, the
spidroins aren't so uniform.
Here they're less ordered,
and they can move and
change shape more freely.
These are called the amorphous regions.
Together, they work like a
network of tiny rigid blocks
connected by elastic cords,
which I have in front of me.
When I pull on the network,
the cords stretch, and they absorb energy.
The blocks don't stretch much,
but each one connects to several cords,
which spreads the pull across the network.
So the amorphous regions
let the silk stretch
while the nanocrystals help it
withstand a much larger pull.
Together, they allow the silk to absorb
a tremendous amount of
energy before breaking,
which makes it so tough.
The result is a material
that's stronger than steel
by weight and also tougher than Kevlar.
It sounds perfect for
making climbing ropes,
parachute cords, airbags,
even bulletproof vests.
But we actually aren't using
spider silk for any of that,
even though we've been
trying to for centuries.
In 1709, a Frenchman
named Francois Xavier Bon
painstakingly collected
hundreds of spider egg sacs,
boiled them, combed them like
wool, spun them into thread,
and then used them to make stockings
that attracted the attention
at the royal court.
But this was harder than it sounds.
As he later said,
"The only difficulty now lies in procuring
a sufficient quantity of spider bags
to make any considerable work of it."
Three centuries later, Simon
Peers and Nicholas Godley
led a years long project in Madagascar,
in which teams of
Malagasy workers gathered
more than a million
golden orb weaver spiders
in the jungle by hand.
They extracted their silk
and painstakingly wove
and embroidered it into
a single golden cape.
Why hadn't they tried
farming the spiders instead?
Well, attempts to do that all
run into the same problem.
Spiders are cannibals.
The big problem with spiders
is that they eat each other?
- That's one of the big problems.
And then you can't just keep them
in a tiny little container.
You're going to have to
have a lot of real estate
if you're going to have a farm
with 10,000 spiders on it.
- [Henry] Even if you could get your hands
on that many spiders, as we've seen,
milking them is difficult,
and the spiders don't always cooperate.
- Really cooperative spider
will give you 300 yards of silk.
100's a lot more typical,
but they kind of have their
own individual personalities.
Some of them will just
break the thread right away,
and not even cooperate with you.
- That's why natural
spider silk is so scarce.
One supplier charges
$700 for 100 milligrams,
which works out to roughly
$7 million per kilogram.
That's roughly 50 times the price of gold.
Okay, so we can't farm
spiders for their silk,
but we know what the proteins are,
so surely we can just make them?
Well, scientists have tried.
By the late 1990s, researchers
at DuPont took the genes
that code for spider silk proteins
and put them into E. coli and yeast.
These living cells are
like protein factories.
One engineered cell
quickly becomes millions.
It worked,
but scientists wanted an
even more efficient method.
So in 2001,
a team in Germany tried
implanting spider silk genes
into plants like tobacco and potatoes.
But if you really want to
produce a lot of protein
in a concentrated form, look at milk.
To feed their young,
mothers produce milk with high
concentrations of proteins.
So around the same time,
a Canadian company called Nexia
tried something much stranger.
They put spider silk genes into goats,
creating genetically
modified spider goats.
No, no, really, they made spider goats.
These goats produce milk
chock-full of spider silk proteins.
In one sense, it worked.
All the experiments were able
to produce spider silk proteins,
but they ran into the same problem.
From E. coli or yeast,
these proteins were purified
as a fine white powder.
From plants, the purified
proteins formed a viscous,
gelatin-like liquid.
And from goats, it was
dissolved in the milk.
None of these even vaguely
resemble spider silk.
- And that's one of the
secrets that any company
that really wants to mimic spider silk
at an industrial scale
needs to kind of figure out
is how to process silk
proteins the way spiders do.
- But that's easier said than done.
In a spider, it all
starts in the silk gland
in a region called tail.
Cells here make proteins called spidroins,
and they secrete them into
the fluid inside the gland.
Every spidroin has three main parts.
One end is called the N-terminal,
and the other the C-terminal.
And between them is a
long repeating sequence
of amino acids.
This is called the repetitive region.
Once inside the tail, the
C-terminal ends pair up,
which links neighboring
spidroins together.
But the N-terminal ends
stay mostly separate.
So the spidroins are still
loose enough to bend,
coil, and move around.
Next, they move into the storage sac,
where they're packed together
at high concentrations.
Normally, proteins this concentrated
would stick to each other,
and clump into a solid,
but this can be modified with
a careful balance of salts
and by changing the pH.
The pH is a measure of the concentration
of hydronium ions in a solution.
And because hydrogen ions
are little positive charges,
you can think of the pH like a dial
that controls the electrical charge
on different parts of the protein.
In the storage sac, the pH is tuned
so that the N-terminal ends
carry a net negative charge.
Every protein carries the same charge.
And since like charges repel,
when you crowd them together,
they shove apart instead
of sticking together.
Now, the spidroins are still crowded
in this aqueous solution, and
at such high concentrations,
they begin to gradually rearrange.
The N-terminals are attracted to water.
These are hydrophilic.
While the repetitive
region is repelled by it,
this is hydrophobic.
So the spidroins rearrange,
and you end up having
these hydrophilic parts
facing outward towards the water.
And hydrophobic parts tuck
themselves inside away from it.
They then form these tiny
structures called micelles.
And the micelles cluster
together into larger globules.
These globules next
enter the spinning duct.
- For the dragline silk, the
duct is kind of S-shaped,
but it gets skinnier and skinnier.
- [Henry] As the globules
go through the narrow duct,
the liquid near the walls
rubs against the surface,
and it moves more slowly,
while the liquid in the
middle moves faster.
So the layers slide past each other,
which is known as shear.
These shear forces stretch
and deform the globule.
- You also remove some
water, so water goes out.
You get a drop in pH, so it
becomes a little bit more acidic
as you go down this duct.
- So the proteins are then being changed
in two ways at once.
Mechanically, they're
being pulled and aligned.
And chemically, that drop in pH
means that there are now
more positive hydronium ions
in the solution.
These bind to the negative
parts of the proteins,
neutralizing them.
Now all the proteins don't
repel each other as strongly,
and so the N-terminal ends begin pairing,
linking the proteins into long chains.
These chains are pulled
through a tiny narrowing
called the drawdown taper,
which leads to the spigot.
Here, the spider pulls the
liquid through a small opening.
This forces the liquid to speed up.
And as it speeds up, it stretches.
It's this final stretch that
pulls neighboring spidroins
tightly alongside one another.
Now, depending on the
sequence of amino acids,
some sections fold into zigzag strands.
These strands then interlock
and rows of hydrogen bonds
stitch them into rigid,
sheet-like structures,
which stack together into the nanocrystals
that give the spider silk its strength.
In other sections, the
spidroins don't fold as neatly.
That's how you get the amorphous regions
which give the silk its stretch.
Exactly how the proteins assemble
inside the spinning duct
is still being studied.
No one fully understands it yet,
and that makes recreating the process
in a lab quite difficult.
So scientists wondered,
"What if instead of starting from scratch,
you used an animal that
already has a spinner?"
This is exactly what researchers
at Kraig BioCraft Laboratories,
a biotech company in Michigan,
have been working on.
What's more, they're
doing it with an insect
that humans have been farming
for nearly 5,000 years.
According to legend,
a Chinese empress was
relaxing in her garden,
when something fell into her teacup.
She looked inside, and saw a cocoon.
The hot water loosened it.
And when she lifted it out,
it unraveled into a
single shimmering thread.
So long that it stretched
across her entire garden.
This was silk.
Whether or not that story's true,
people eventually learned
to farm the insect
that made the thread.
(jaunty music)
Silkworms.
They're the caterpillars of
the domesticated silk moth.
Silk quickly became one of
the most valuable materials
in the land.
It dressed emperors and spurred trade
connecting East Asia and Europe.
So much so that it gave
the trade route its name,
the Silk Road.
For nearly 2,000 years,
China guarded the secret.
But of course, people were
always trying to steal it.
By the mid-sixth century,
the Byzantine Empire was in trouble.
Plague had devastated the population.
And on top of that,
the purchase of silk
was draining its gold.
The problem was that
Byzantines couldn't make silk.
Most of it had to come through Persia,
the very empire it was fighting.
So Emperor Justinian made a
secret deal with two monks.
They would travel east,
find the source of silk,
and then smuggle it back.
They returned with a secret
hidden inside their hollow canes.
Silkworm eggs.
This may be the first recorded case
of industrial espionage in history.
With that, Byzantium could
finally make its own silk.
Nowadays, we farm them by the millions.
- One moth lays 500 eggs.
- [Henry] Okay.
- So when you talk about
growing productions, right?
Like my wife and I had a baby.
These guys, they have 500 babies.
And they do it every 30 days.
- So the researchers at Kraig wondered,
"What if we could make the silkworm
spin spider silk instead?"
- When we create a transgenic silkworm,
we're taking the genetics of a silkworm,
and the genetics of a spider,
and we're putting those together.
We're taking the best aspects of both.
And that's what we're
doing to create our fibers.
- [Henry] They start by
gluing eggs onto a slide,
which they line up under a microscope.
- So this is the microinjection station.
We're talking about eggs
that are the size of the head of a pen.
We're talking about needles
that are half a micron in diameter.
- This part is the, I want to inject.
So as you see, this is the tungsten needle
and this is the glass capillary.
And first we poke a hole
with the tungsten needle.
I will actually move the eggs
to the capillary and poke.
- The fluid carrying the spider DNA
is then injected into the part of the egg
that will eventually become the silkworm.
But at this point, the
genes are still separate.
They have to become part
of the silkworm's own DNA.
And luckily, nature already
has a way of doing that.
If you take an insect like a moth
and look inside its genome,
you'll see some stretches
of DNA that move around.
They jump from one place
in the genome to another.
These are called jumping
genes, or transposons.
One specific one is called piggyBac,
and it was first identified
in a cabbage looper moth.
PiggyBac is a piece of DNA
with two short sequences at its ends,
and it works together with an enzyme
that recognizes these ends,
cuts the whole piece out,
and inserts it somewhere
else in the genome,
kind of like a natural
cut and paste system.
What scientists realized
is that if the enzyme
only looks at the two ends,
then you can keep those ends the same,
but change what sits in the middle,
and use that to implant
the DNA of your choosing.
So in the lab, the DNA in the middle
is replaced with the spider silk gene.
This, together with separate instructions
for making the enzyme,
is what's then injected
into the silkworm egg.
And inside the egg,
the enzyme recognizes the
familiar end sequences and cuts
and inserts the spider silk
gene into the silkworm's DNA.
If everything works, it
becomes a permanent part
of the silkworm's genome.
Now with silkworm where the edit worked
looks almost exactly
like one where it didn't.
- [Jon] The first approach we used
was creating transgenics
with the glowing cocoon.
A green fluorescent protein is
what's making these guys glow
that green color under
this particular wavelength
with that particular light
filter in front of it.
- [Henry] It feels magical.
And there's a living thing inside of it.
- [Jon] Mm hmm, yep.
- [Henry] And it's creating
the glowing effect.
- [Jon] Yeah.
- [Henry] But even if the
DNA insertion is successful,
it might not have ended
up in the right place.
- If I create the world's best recipe
for chocolate chip cookies,
and I stick it in the pasta section-
- [Henry] Yeah.
- You're probably not going to make
a lot of chocolate chip cookies, right?
'Cause you're not going to see it.
- [Henry] Yeah.
- Same thing for this, right?
We want the recipe in the right section
of the right cookbook.
- That's why getting the spider silk gene
into the silkworm isn't enough.
- We really want the spider
silk get incorporated
into their silk gland,
not any other tissue.
- [Henry] But piggyBac only looks
for a four-letter DNA sequence.
TTAA.
- There's so many TTAA in their genome.
You couldn't really
control where they were.
- [Henry] So it's like there
are a lot of different places
where they could park.
- Yeah, yeah, that's true!
- And that means that it
won't spin pure spider silk.
If you had to estimate,
of the transgenic silk,
like what percentage is spider DNA?
- Like 6%, 10%.
- That's insane to me!
So even with this limited gene transfer,
the fibers still achieve much
of the mechanical performance
of pure spider silk.
- Our average samples are usually about
60% of spider silk, right?
Which, show me any
other place in the world
where you can get materials
that perform at 60% the strength
of spider silk that you can
make cost effectively, right?
- [Henry] To push the
60% average even higher,
the insertion needs to be more targeted.
- The next step is to create pure,
what are called
knock-in/knockout transgenics
where we will completely
remove all aspects
of the silkworm's native DNA for the silk,
and replace that completely
with the spider silk protein.
- And to do that, most of
the leading labs in the field
are exploring CRISPR-Cas9.
This tool has two parts.
The first is a guide, a
short piece of genetic code
designed to match one
exact stretch of DNA.
Unlike piggyBac,
which recognizes a sequence
just four DNA letters long,
this guide matches about 20 letters,
making it far more specific.
The second is a cutting protein.
When the guide finds
its matching sequence,
the protein cuts the DNA.
Here, that spot is inside
the silkworm's own gene
for making silk.
The cell immediately
tries to repair the break,
and scientists take advantage of this
by also injecting donor DNA,
carrying the spider silk gene.
As the cell repairs the cut,
it copies in that donor DNA,
stitching the spider silk gene
into this one precise location.
But this process is still
an active development.
And Kraig is not the only group
chasing the dream of spider silk.
In Germany, AMSilk is
making proteins for fibers,
coatings, powders, and hydrogels.
And in Japan, Spiber is
brewing protein fibers
through fermentation.
Brands like Goldwin and The North Face
have already used a
version of these fibers
in their clothing.
And the military has been interested too.
In 2016, the US Army funded Kraig
to produce ballistic shoe packs,
panels layered with transgenic silk
that are designed as potential body armor.
And it's even being explored in medicine.
For centuries,
surgeons have stitched
wounds together with silk.
But now a company called
Newrotex is using spider silk
to help repair damaged nerves.
So if it can be produced cheaply,
spider silk could find
its way into clothing,
armor, implants, even nerve repair.
But to do that, we're
going to need a lot of it.
- And this is our specialized
spider silk. There you go.
- This is the transgenic spider silk.
- [Jon] This is spider silk.
This is transgenic spider silk.
- What? This is like a bale.
This is a hay bale of spider silk.
- So last year we produced
about a half a ton
of spider silk cocoon.
- Half a ton.
- And this is silk from that.
- But what about our original question?
Can you use transgenic spider
silk to swing like Spider-Man?
So Derek, I've got you
here in a climbing gym
for a very good reason.
And the reason is underneath
this dirty dish towel.
- Unveil it, unveil it. Yeah, go.
All right, okay. This
looks very uninspiring.
- [Henry] So what's interesting is
this is one continuous filament.
- This is just one strand.
- But each one of these strands
is actually 10 individual silk filaments
that are kind of connected.
- All right.
So you want me to hang from this?
- I do want you to hang from it, yes.
I actually want you to do
more than just hang from it.
I want you to swing.
- This will be the first time ever
anyone has ever swung
from actual spider silk.
Granted this spider silk came
from other organisms, but...
(mysterious music)
I don't know if it's going to
hold my weight, so let's see.
In three, two, one.
- You really came close!
(Derek and Henry laughing)
(dramatic music)
(dramatic music continues)
- Don't tell anyone, but Spider-Man.
(dramatic music)
- Okay, so we've seen
it can hold your weight
pretty reasonably.
We could swing, but I do want
to put it to the ultimate test
and get you up there.
How much do you trust spider silk?
- Tensile strength doesn't lie.
- All right, let's get you up there.
(tense music)
- We used the title,
"Risking my life to settle
a physics debate" too early.
(tense music)
It feels like it's going
to dig into my fingers.
- [Speaker] This is crazy.
(tense music)
(tense music continues)
(Derek yelling)
- I'm going to go. I'm going to go!
(tense music)
- [Henry] Whoo!
(Derek yelling)
Let's go!
- You got to see my finger, man!
- [Henry] Ooh, damn!
- Yeah. This is the
problem with spider silk.
Just, it's thin, it's strong,
and it just rips you open.
- Now, if it isn't clear,
we're not exactly web-swinging experts.
But we'd love to get the
silk into of the hands
of someone who is.
- Tom Holland, this is a challenge.
Yeah, I'm calling out Tom Holland.
I'm calling out all them guys.
Andrew Garfield, Tobey McGuire.
That's right. Come at me, bro.
(electronic music)
- See, spider silk is so strong
and so thin that it
actually cut Derek's skin.
And that's actually a great way
to explain the design
flaw with modern razors.
Thanks to Henson Shaving
for sponsoring this video.
See, facial hair resists
more than you think.
And many razor blades
are engineered so thin
that they bend under that resistance.
This is called blade flex.
Now, most razors actually
build this flex in.
They use springs, pivots,
and flexible mounts that
allow the blade to move.
It's supposed to make
the shave feel gentler,
but it means that the cutting
angle is constantly changing.
When unsupported, the
blade bends mid-stroke
and instead of slicing cleanly,
it tugs the hairs, micro-cutting the skin.
That's what causes irritation.
The usual fixes are lubrication
strips or extra blades,
but they don't solve the real problem.
The blade is still allowed to flex.
We assume that razor bumps
and irritation are inevitable,
but that's shaped by bad design.
But Henson is designed
by aerospace machinists
who control cutting forces
with high precision.
And their razors use a single
precisely-machined blade.
Instead of letting it move,
Henson's design supports the cutting edge
with tight machining tolerances,
holding the blade securely
so the angle is consistent.
Remove the flex, remove the irritation.
Use code "Veritasium" for 100 free blades
with any razor purchase.
Just add both the razor
and blades to your cart.
Thanks to Henson Shaving,
and as always, thanks for watching.